alternet.org 2004-06-02

# AlterNet: Privacy Policy

Content Files

**Election 2004**  
The most important election of your life.

**Rights& Liberties**  
Human rights and civil liberties.

**MediaCulture**  
Critical perspectives on our media-driven world.

**Movie Mix**  
Home of The Alternative Movie Awards.

**War on Iraq**  
Coverage of America's war with Iraq.

**DrugReporter**  
News from the front lines of the drug war.

**EnviroHealth**  
From climate change to medical news.

Feedback

Tell us how we're doing.

 Discussion

Visit AlterNet's forums for lively discussions on today's news.  
**Guests »**  
**Members »**

|  |  |  | 

AlterNet Privacy Policy

AlterNet, and our parent organization, the Independent Media Institute, guarantee that we will never, under any circumstances, sell, trade or make public your personal information, unless you designate otherwise. All personal information you provide will remain confidential. In addition, you always will have the option to edit the information provided to us or to have your personal information removed from our records.

**Traffic Data**

When you visit AlterNet, our systems collect basic information about your computer, including: IP address (your computer's unique signature), operating system (e.g., Windows 95), browser software (e.g., Microsoft Internet Explorer, Netscape), Internet Service Provider (e.g., AOL). We also collect information about what you view on the site. This information reflects our readership as a whole and is used to help us better understand the AlterNet community.

**Use of Cookies**

AlterNet employs cookies -- small text files placed on your computer's hard drive -- to track the type of content and sites to which our users link, the length of time they spend at any particular site and the AlterNet services they use. Cookies also help us diagnose problems with our server.

For more on cookies, please [click here](http://help.netscape.com/kb/consumer/19970226-2.html).

**Email Newsletters and "Send a Friend" Feature**

After signing up online, users will receive email newsletters and other occasional announcements from AlterNet. In order to distribute our email, we collect subscribers' email addresses. We do not share addresses with other companies or partners. Users can unsubscribe from email newsletters at any time.

AlterNet offers a "send this story to a friend" feature, which allows our users to inform others about an article they might be interested in. For this feature to function, we ask for email addresses from the sender and for the recipient. We do not store or save these addresses and you will not receive any communication from AlterNet or its partners as a result of having used this feature.

**Discussion Forums**

AlterNet makes discussion forums available to its users. Please remember any information disclosed in these areas becomes publicly available, and therefore you should exercise caution when disclosing personal information.

If you have any concerns about the discussion forums, send email to [discuss@alternet.org](mailto:discuss@alternet.org).

**Surveys**

From time to time AlterNet will conduct voluntary surveys of site visitors to obtain aggregate demographic information about them. This information may be compiled and shared in the aggregate with third parties, but no personal details will be traceable or associated with specific individuals.

**Linking to Other Sites**

AlterNet contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

**Children's Guidelines**

Protecting the rights of children is important to us. As a result, we do not collect or maintain any information from individuals we know to be under 13 years old, and no part of AlterNet is intended to attract anyone under 13.

**Unsubscribe, Data Removal and Data Modification Policies**

AlterNet allows users to opt-out of receiving communications from us and to modify or remove their information from our system. The following options are available to do so:

  * Send email to [support@alternet.org](mailto:support@alternet.org);
  * send mail to: AlterNet, 77 Federal St., San Francisco, CA 94107;
  * call: 415/284-1420.

**Other Disclosure of Personal Information**

AlterNet will not use or disclose your personal information without your consent, except (i) as described in this privacy policy or (ii) as required by law, court order or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority. This policy does not protect information you post to any online bulletin board or other public forum within our website.

**Contacting AlterNet**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

AlterNet  
77 Federal St.  
San Francisco, CA 94107  

AlterNet reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement at any time without notice, and only the current Privacy Statement may be deemed effective.

**« Home**

|  |  |  | 

Buy This Book

**The Five Biggest Lies Bush Told Us About Iraq** dissects how the president exploited 9/11 in order to wage a misguided war of empire.

Support AlterNet

Do you value the information you're getting from AlterNet? Please show your support with a **tax-deductible donation**.

|
